Guide to the Frank Baker papers, 1641-2002 and undated, bulk 1740-1995 RL.00069
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Research Series, 1642, 1669, 1731-1797, 1922-1993 and undated, 48 boxes
  - Other Publications Subseries, 1808-1991 and undated
    - 1950s Publications
      - John Cennick (1718-55): A Handlist of his Writings (Hart124, 1958), 1958 (Box 201)
      - 'Mad Grimshaw' and his Covenants with God: a study in Eighteenth Century Psychology (Hart125, 1958), 1958 (Box 201)
      - Hail thou once despised Jesus: The Story of the Author of a Well-Known Hymn, 1958 (Box 201)
      - Methodism's Oldest Church, 1959 (Box 201)
    - 1960s Publications
      - John Fletcher, Methodist Clergyman (Hart132, 1960), 1960 (Box 201)
      - John Wesley's Churchmanship (Hart133, 1960), 1958 (Box 201)
      - Let's Start an Argument, 1962 (Box 201)
      - The Frank Baker Collection: An Autobiographical Analysis (Hart138, 1962), 1962 (Box 201)
      - Wesley's Puritan Ancestry (Hart142, 1962), 1962 (Box 201)
      - Aldersgate 1738-1963: the Challenge of Aldersgate [address], 1963 (Box 201)
      - The Beginnings of American Methodism (Hart144, 1963), 1963 (Box 201)
      - John Wesley on Christian Perfection (Hart146, 1963), 1963 (Box 201)
      - When Did Methodism Begin? (Hart147, 1963), 1963 (Box 201)
      - Adult Teacher articles, 1963, 1964 (Box 201)
      - Captain Thomas Webb, Pioneer of American Methodism (Hart154, 1965), 1965 (Box 201)
      - John Bennet and Early Methodist Polity (Hart157, 1965), undated (Box 201)
      - Aldersgate and Wesley's Editors (Hart160, 1966), 1964-1966 and undated, 2 folders (Box 201)
      - The Doctrines in the Discipline (Hart161, 1966), 1808, 1972 and undated (Box 201)
      - John Wesley's First Marriage (Hart162, 1966), 1966, 1967 and undated (Box 201)
      - The Lay Pioneers of American Methodism (Hart165, 1967), 1965-1966 (Box 201)
      - Encyclopaedia Britannica essays on John and Charles Wesley, 1967 (Box 202)
      - American Methodism: Beginnings and Endings (Hart166, 1968), 1967 (Box 202)
      - John Wesley and the Moravians of Fulneck (Hart167, 1968), 1968 (Box 202)
      - Chambers's Encyclopedia essays on John Wesley, Charles Wesley, and Methodism (Hart168, 1968), 1968 (Box 202)
      - Wesley's Early Preachers in America (Hart171, 1969), 1969 (Box 202)
    - 1970s Publications
      - The Birth of John Wesley's Journal (Hart172, 1970), 1970 (Box 202)
      - Wesley and William Law: A Reconsideration (Hart174, 1970), 1970 (Box 202)
      - The Frank Baker Collection of Wesleyana and British Methodism (1970), 1970 (Box 202)
      - The Oxford Edition of Wesley's Works (Hart175, 1970), 1970 (Box 202)
      - A United Methodist Heritage Tour of England (Hart176, 1970), 1970, 2 folders (Box 202)
      - Wesleyana and British Methodism (Hart177, 1970), 1970 (Box 202)
        Photocopy from Gnomon: Essays for the Dedication of the William R. Perkins Library, April 16, 1970.
      - Whitefield's Break with the Wesleys (Hart178, 1970), 1970 (Box 202)
      - 'Come over and Help Us' -- America to Wesley (Hart180, 1971), 1971 (Box 202)
      - Dr. Thomas Coke and Methodism in the Isle of Wight (Hart181, 1971), 1971 (Box 202)
      - Was John Wesley Real (Hart188, 1973), 1973 (Box 202)
      - The Real John Wesley (Hart190, 1974), 1969, 1973, 1974 and undated (Box 202)
      - Americanizing of Methodism (Hart191, 1975), 1975 (Box 202)
      - Edward Evans, Founding Philadelphia Methodist [letter] (Hart192, 1975), 1975 (Box 202)
      - John Wesley, Literary Arbiter: an Introduction to his Use of the Asterisk (Hart193, 1975), undated (Box 202)
      - The British Background of North Carolina Methodism (Hart196, 1976), 1976, 2 folders (Box 203)
      - John Wesley and the Bible (Hart198, 1976), 1976 (Box 203)
      - John Wesley's Last Visit to Charleston (Hart201, 1977), 1977 (Box 203)
      - The Trans-Atlantic Triangle: Relations Between British, Canadian and American Methodism during Wesley's Lifetime (Hart204, 1979), 1979 (Box 203)
      - The World Methodist Family, 1979, 1993 (Box 203)
    - 1980s publications
      - John Wesley and Bishop Joseph Butler: a Fragment of John Wesley's Manuscript Journal, 16th to 24th August 1739 (Hart205, 1980), 1980 (Box 203)
      - Methodism (Hart206, 1980), 1980, 2 folders (Box 203)
      - Susanna Wesley: Puritan, Parent, Pastor, Protagonist, Pattern (Hart207, 1980), 1980, 3 folders (Box 203)
      - Unfolding John Wesley: a Survey of Twenty Years' Studies in Wesley's Thought (Hart208, 1983), 1980, 2 folders (Box 204)
      - John Wesley and the German Pietists in Georgia (Hart210, 1981), 1940, 1973-1983, and undated, 2 folders (Box 204)
      - John Wesley, Postal Pastor (Hart211, 1980, 1981), 1980 (Box 204)
      - Publishing to the Glory of God: John Wesley as Seen in his Writings (Hart212, 1982), 1982 (Box 204)
      - John Wesley and America (Hart217, 1984), 1984 (Box 204)
      - John Wesley, London Publisher, 1733-1791: a Lecture to the Friends of Wesley's Chapel, Given on Thursday May 24th 1984 at Wesley's Chapel (Hart218, 1984), 1984 (Box 204)
      - John Wesley and the Birth of the Methodist Episcopal Church (Hart222, 1985), 1983-1984, 2 folders (Box 204)
      - The Status of Methodist Preachers in America, 1769-1791 (Hart224, 1985), 1985 (Box 204)
      - A Memorial Statement for Franz Hildebrandt, D.D., Ph.D., Lic. Theol. (1909-1985) (Hart227, 1986), 1985 and undated (Box 204)
      - Re-creating John Wesley in the World Methodist Museum, 1985 (Box 204)
      - Wesley's Principles for Social Action (Hart228, 1986), 1986 (Box 204)
      - The Apostle of Methodism in the South Seas (Hart229, 1987) and Methodist Pioneers in the South Pacific (Hart233, 1987), 1940-1988 and undated, 5 folders (Box 205)
        Includes correspondence, drafts, and research.
      - Contributions to the World Encyclopedia (Hart 230, 231, 232, 235), 1982-1987 (Box 205)
      - John Wesley and Practical Divinity (Hart234, 1987), 1986 (Box 205)
        For possibly related material, see also the folder on Practical Divinity in Subject Files Series, Alphabetical Subseries.
      - The Beginnings of Methodism in Lincolnshire, 1987 (Box 205)
      - Introduction to John Wesley: Contemporary Perspectives (Hart237, 1988), 1987-1989 and undated, folders 1-2 of 4 (Box 205)
      - Introduction to John Wesley: Contemporary Perspectives (Hart237, 1988), 1987-1989 and undated, folders 3-4 of 4 (Box 206)
      - John Wesley's Publishing Apprenticeship (Hart240, 1988), 1983-1988 (Box 206)
      - John Wesley at Leisure, correspondence (Hart243, 1989), 1989 (Box 206)
      - John Wesley at Leisure, printed materials (Hart243), 1988-1989 (Box 206)
      - John Wesley, Biblical Commentator (Hart244, 1989), 1988-1989 (Box 206)
    - 1990s and Other Publications
      - Eyewitnesses to Early Methodism (Hart246, 1990), 1990 (Box 206)
      - Charles Wesley's Letters (Hart 247, 1991), 1991 (Box 207)
      - A Poet in Love: The Courtship of Charles Wesley, 1747-1749 (Hart249, 1991), 1824, 1991 and undated, 3 folders (Box 207)
      - The Blackwell Dictionary of Evangelical Biography, 1730-1860--articles and correspondence, 1991-1995 and undated, 2 folders (Box 207)
        Baker contributed articles on the following people: John Anderson; Francis Asbury; William Atherton; John Barber; Thomas Barber; Andrew Blair; Thomas Blanshard; William Briggs; Thomas Brisco; Agnes Bulmer; John Clayton; Jonathan Coussins; James Creighton; John Crook; Jonathan Crowther; William Grimshaw; James Hamilton; Edward Hare; John Kershaw; Thomas Richards; Sir James Stonhouse; Zechariah and Mary Barritt Taft; Thomas Thompson; and Thomas Westell (or Westall).
      - Sixty Years on the Wesley Trail, 1993 (Box 207)
      - The World Methodist Family (circa 1994), 1993 (circa 1993, no Hart number) (Box 207)
      - Review: Spiritual Pilgrim: A Reassessment of the life of the Countess of Huntingdon by Edwin Welch, 1995 (Box 207)
      - Historical Dictionary of Methodism (1996)--articles on Charles Wesley, discipline, evangelism, the love-feast, and watch-night, 1994 and undated (Box 207)
      - Probing a Wesley Letter, 1996 (Box 207)
      - The Texts of Hymns on the Great Festivals, 1996 (Box 207)
      - Re-setting Jacob's Dislocated Thigh, 1997 (Box 207)
      - Robert Williams, for American National Biography (1999), undated (Box 207)
      - The Metamorphosis of Charles Wesley's Christmas Hymns, 1739-1788 (2001), 1991 and undated (Box 207)
      - Reviews, notices, and clippings about Frank Baker's works, 1957-1980 and undated (Box 207)
      - Reviews by Frank Baker, 1957-1996 and undated (Box 208)
        Contains a variety of reviews of other scholars' work, including short book reviews, essay-length reviews, and reader reports on articles and books and being considered for publication by various journals and publishers. Materials comprised mainly of typescripts and clippings with a scattering of correspondence. Arranged in chronological order.
  - Unpublished Writings Subseries, 1642, 1669, 1731-1797, 1923-1928, 1937-1962, 1983-1985 and undated
    Articles, essays, reviews, creative writing, and other pieces left unfinished at Baker's death. Early dates reflect content of copies, not necessarily original document from that date. Arranged alphabetically by working title. Contains work for which proof of publication could not be established when materials were processed. Hart bibliography documents Baker's publications only through 1991, and some of the manuscripts gathered in this subseries could have reached print under other titles after that date.
    - A Methodist Hymn Writer?, undated (Box 208)
    - An Early Critic of American Methodism, undated (Box 208)
    - Annals of Methodism, 1700-1800, undated (Box 208)
    - Assurance of Personal Salvation, undated (Box 208)
    - Broken Falls, undated [Original missing.] (Box 208)
    - Brother Saul, 1972, and undated (Box 208)
    - Can We Trust the Gospels?, undated (Box 208)
    - Charles Wesley and His Hymns, 1990 Aug. 1 (Box 208)
      Notes and research, apparently for an address to be given at Asbury Theological Seminary in August, 1990. Undetermined as to whether this address was ever delivered or published.
    - The Christian's Amusement, undated (Box 208)
    - Christmas without Christ?, undated (Box 208)
    - Communicating the Gospel in Early Methodism, undated (Box 208)
    - Concordance to the Poetical Works of Edward Young, 1713, 1741, circa 1770, 1854, 1918, 1950-1987, and undated, folders 1-3 of 8 (Box 208)
    - Concordance to the Poetical Works of Edward Young, 1713, 1741, circa 1770, 1854, 1918, 1950-1987, and undated, folders 4-8 of 8 (Box 209)
    - Drafts, research and correspondence on short articles, 1958-1960 (Box 209)
      Short articles submitted to The Methodist Recorder and New Christian Advocate. Publication could not be verified. Titles include: Richard Boardman, The Oldest Methodist Church in the World, A Brown Bread Preacher, What God has Wrought, He That Believeth Shall Not Make Haste, Hail, Thou Once Despised Jesus, The Methodist Portfolio
    - Dr. Bray's Associates and Georgia, circa 1947 (Box 209)
    - The Early Methodist Conference, undated (Box 209)
    - Early Methodist Worship: The Watchnight Service, undated (Box 209)
      Draft, circa 5000 words, of what appears to be an address, although time and place of its delivery or publication cannot be established. Baker's handwritten notes indicate his calculations about "minutes per page," presumably to be read aloud.
    - Eayrs Essays, 1937-1961 and undated, 3 folders (Box 209)
      Contains correspondence, John Wesley's Christian Library, and The Unrest in Methodism, 1790-1800.
    - Failure, a Meditation given by Frank Baker, York Chapel, Duke Divinity School, 1965 (Box 210)
    - Francis Asbury - Father in God of American Methodism, 1971 (Box 210)
    - Francis Asbury, Founder of American Methodism, circa 1995 (Box 210)
    - Francis Asbury--John Wesley's Episcopal Apprentice, undated (Box 210)
    - The Frustrations of the Faithful, a Meditation given by Frank Baker, York Chapel, Duke Divinity School, 1965 (Box 210)
    - The Grand Depositum, circa 1940-1949 (Box 210)
    - Hymns of John and Charles Wesley, 1966 (Box 210)
    - In Wesley's Day, undated (Box 210)
      Series of titles under together In Wesley's Day
    - Jesus Christ Our Lord, undated (Box 210)
    - John and Charles Wesley, Two Brothers in Evangelism, 1988-1991 and undated (Box 210)
    - John Wesley, E.A.P.J., 1961 and undated (Box 210)
    - John Wesley and His Sons in the Gospel: or 'Thomas in the Tapestry of God', 1990 (Box 210)
    - John Wesley and the Methodist Family, (circa 1950-1959) (Box 210)
    - John Wesley and the S.P.G., circa 1947 (Box 210)
    - John Wesley on Creationism and Traducianism, (circa 1991) -- Correspondence, Drafts, and Research 1642, 1783, 1983, 1991 and undated, 3 folders (Box 210)
    - John Wesley on Separation from the Church, undated (Box 210)
    - John Wesley's Birthday Reflections, 1741, 1987 (Box 210)
    - Journalism excercises, 1934 (Box 210)
    - Killiam's 'Martin Luther' Pamphlet and Episcope in Methodism, undated (Box 210)
    - Lectures and lecture notes on various topics, undated (Box 210)
    - Lectures on poetry, undated (Box 211)
      Series of lectures; date and place of delivery unknown. Titles include: Fun With the Poets, Limericks, The Nature of Poetry Religious Poetry English Literature Before Chaucer John Greenleaf Whittier, The Man and his Poems
    - Letters from London, undated (Box 211)
    - Methodism and the Lovefeast, undated (Box 211)
    - Methodism and the 'Rude, Populous North,' undated (Box 211)
    - Methodism and the Trade Unions, the Wesley Historical Society Lecture, undated (Box 211)
    - Methodism in Hull Kingston-upon-Hull, undated (Box 211)
    - Methodist Recorder, What's Puzzling You?, undated (Box 211)
    - Miss Sarah Wesley of Bristol - A Methodist Bluestocking, circa 1940-1949 (Box 211)
    - Northanger Abbey by Jane Austen, undated (Box 211)
    - Nunc Dimittis, circa 1940-1949 (Box 211)
    - Our Methodist Heritage, undated (Box 211)
    - Portraits with Multiple Plates in Methodist Magazines, 1778-1839, undated (Box 211)
    - Primitive Methodist Bibliography (circa 1966) -- Research, 1937-1940, and undated (Box 211)
    - Printers' Flowers as Bibliographic Evidence, 1669, 1731-1797, 1923, 1928, 1962, 1983-1985, and undated (Box 211-220)
      Extensive research, plans, and notes for unpublished article on 18th century printers' flowers (or fleurons). Includes a draft and appendix. Folders containing Baker's more extensive notes and thoughts on this article, along with photocopied articles by other writers on this topic, are arranged at the beginning of this folder group; following these, the remaining folders are arranged alphabetically by topic (most often a printer's surname).
    - The Purgatory of Suicides, undated (Box 220)
    - The Relations between Methodism and the Anglican Church: 1791-1800, 1946-1948 (Box 220)
    - Rupert Eric Davies, undated (Box 220)
    - Samuel Wesley Poems, 1736: Concordance of Key Words, undated, 4 folders (Box 220)
      Undetermined whether this is Baker's work.
    - Scriptural Holiness, 1986 (Box 221)
    - Secret Marriages, circa 1940-1949 (Box 221)
    - The Secret of Revival: Preaching or Prayer?, circa 1940-1949 (Box 221)
    - The Significance of John Wesley, undated (Box 221)
    - The Significance of the Sacrament in Early Methodism, undated (Box 221)
    - Some Thoughts on John Wesley and His Works, 1978 (Box 221)
    - To the Voluntary Custodians of Wesley's House, London. A Personal Word by Frank Baker, undated (Box 221)
    - Unto You, a sermon preached in Duke University Chapel by Frank Baker, 1968 (Box 221)
    - Wesley and Propertius, undated (Box 221)
    - Wesley as Preacher-Publisher, circa 1970s, and undated, 3 folders (Box 221)
      Undetermined whether this is related to Hart 218, "John Wesley, London Publisher"--see Writings and Research Series, Other Publications Subseries.
    - Wesley's England, 1991 and undated (Box 221)
    - Wesley Family, undated (Box 221)
    - Wesleys in Georgia, 1972 (Box 221)
    - Wesley on Spirituality, 1985 (Box 221)
    - Wesley's Private Prayers, undated (Box 221)
    - Wesley's Use of Hebrew, undated (Box 221)
      Not verified as Baker's work.
    - What Hath God Wrought, 1959 (Box 221)
    - William Grimshaw and George Whitefield, undated (Box 221)
    - The Women and the Babe, a Nativity Play, 1944, 2 folders (Box 221)
    - Word to a Drunkard, circa 1940-1949 (Box 221)
    - Unpublished creative works: play scripts, undated, folders 1 of 4 (Box 221)
    - Unpublished creative works: play scripts, undated, folders 2-4 of 4 (Box 222)
    - Unpublished creative works: poems, undated (Box 222)
    - Unpublished creative works: short stories, undated (Box 222)
    - Unpublished creative works: short stories and rejection slips, 1934-1938 and undated (Box 222)
    - Unpublished fragments by genre: articles, essays, and reviews, 1946-1947, 1983-1984, and undated (Box 222)
      Notes and partial drafts for various untitled or unidentified articles and addresses. Topics include, but are not limited to, the following: JW's last visit to Alnwick; JW and his nephew Samuel; remarks for a Symposium on Methodism, 1983, at Duke University Divinity School; remarks for a panel on the "Present State and Future Shape of Theology in the Wesleyan Tradition," 1984, also at Duke University Divinity School.
    - Unpublished fragments by genre: cameos, skits, sketches, and verse, 1930s-1940s (Box 222)
  - Writings By Others Subseries, circa 1925-1995 and undated
    - Action, Reaction, and Interaction: Report of a Residential Conference on Methodist History Held at Westhill College, Sally Oak, 5th-8th April 1983, 1983 (Box 223)
    - The Addresses of Bishop Ivan Lee Holt of St. Louis, Mo., and Bishop Nolan B. Harmon of Charlotte, N.C., at the Unveiling of a Commemorative Monument Recalling the First Meeting of the Commissioners on Unity of the Northern and Southern Branches of American Methodism held at Cape May, New Jersey, August 17-23, 1876, First Methodist Church, Cape May, N.J., 1961 (Box 223)
    - Albin, Thomas, R., Early Methodist Letters, 1988-1989, 17 folders (Box 223-225)
      Extensive printouts of data derived from unpublished doctoral research Albin conducted at Cambridge University, circa 1978-1982. Compiles the texts and lists the archival sources of several hundred Methodist letters and autobiographies written between 1725 and 1790. The first ten folders contain the raw data; the final seven folders contain indexes of the material sorted by various criteria, such as author, date, and preachers' station. Albin made this research available to Baker to use in the late 1980s when he was serving as Textual Editor of the Wesley Bicentennial Edition.
    - Andrews, Dee, 1984-1988 and undated (Box 225)
    - Bancroft, G.H. The Early History of Methodism in Furness, undated (Box 225)
    - Bangs, Carl, The Two Sources of Methodist Ministry, 1983 (Box 225)
    - Berger, Teresa, Charles Wesley und sein Liedgut: eine Literaturubersicht, 1988 (Box 225)
    - Bethea, Joseph B, Black Methodists in North Carolina, 1975 (Box 225)
    - Biggs, Barry, Nonconformist Records and their Users, 1974 (Box 225)
    - Birrell, Augustine, John Wesley, 1703-1791, 1925 (Box 225)
    - Borgen, Ole E., John Wesley on the Sacraments, 1972 and undated, 2 folders (Box 225)
    - Brake, G. Thompson, Rev., David Pilgrim, undated (Box 225)
    - Braswell, George, Civil Religion in Contemporary Iran, undated (Box 225)
    - Briggs, John P. and John Briggs, Unholy Desires, Inordinate Affections: A Psychodynamic Inquiry into John Wesley's Relationship with Women, 1990 (Box 225)
    - Brockwell, Charles W., Methodist Discipline: From Rule of Life to Canon Law, 1984, 1985 (Box 225)
    - Brown, Ford K., Fathers of the Victorians: The Age of Wilberforce, 1961 (Box 225)
    - Bunker, Laurence H. and E.A. Desbois, They Lived in Israel, (1960) -- correspondence and draft, 1958-1959 and undated (Box 225)
    - Butterfield, Herbert, Historical Development of the Principle of Toleration in British Life, 1956 (Box 225)
    - Butterworth, Richard, Wesley's Interviews with Famous People, undated (Box 225)
    - Callaway, C. Wayne, John Wesley's Primitive Physick: An Essay in Appreciation, 1973 (Box 225)
    - Campbell, Ted A., 5 folders (Box 226)
      Four articles: John Wesley's Conception of Christian Antiquity as a Model for Church Renewal, 1980; John Wesley's Conceptions and Uses of Christian Antiquity, 1985 (book proposal based on diss.); The Religion of the Heart: A Shift in Forms of European and British Religious Life, 1618-1812, circa 1989-1990 (2 folders); and Studies in John Wesley's Theology: A Bibliography, 1988.
    - Cannon, Dean, A Methodist Heritage from the Conference of 1784, 1960 (Box 226)
    - Case, Leland D., 1964 (Box 226)
    - Cate, Margaret Davis, The Wesleys on Saint Simons Island, undated (Box 226)
    - Chamberlayne, J. H., From Sect to Church in British Methodism, 1964 (Box 226)
    - Chambers, W.A., Catholic Spirituality and the General Rules of the United Societies, 1981 (Box 226)
    - Charles Wesley Publication Colloquium--presented papers later published as Charles Wesley: Poet and Theologian, 1989-1990, 2 folders (Box 226)
    - Clapper, Gregory, John Wesley on Religious Affection, undated (Box 226)
    - Clark, Elmer T.Francis Asbury's Last Journey, 1955 (Box 226)
    - Clark, Elmer T. Notes on the Early Travels of Bishop Francis Asbury in South Carolina, Georiga, and the Holston Country, 1955 (Box 226)
      For related material, see Subject Files, Alphabetical I, Asbury, Francis
    - Clark, F.L., John Frith, Kentish Martyr, 1503-1533, 1978 (Box 226)
    - Cole, Rev. R. Lee, An Old Diary, Drumsna, Billy Bray, 1956 (Box 227)
    - Cox, Leo, John Wesley's Concept of Perfection, 1961 (Box 227)
    - Crookshank, C.H., Wesley's Work in Ireland, undated (Box 227)
    - Cubie, David L. Wesley's Doctrines of Sanctification and the Church, in Wesleyan Theological Perspectives: The Church, (1984) undated (Box 227)
    - Cumbers, Frank, The Romance of Methodist Literature: Two Hundred Years of Publishing, undated (Box 227)
    - Cushman, Robert, Fifty Years of Theology and Theological Education at Duke; Retrospect and Prospect, 1977-1978 (Box 227)
    - Davis, Charles M., Green Hill - Pioneer, Patriot and Preacher, 1969 (Box 227)
    - Davies, Rupert E., John Wesley in Modern Scholarship, 1977 (Box 227)
    - Davison, Hugh A., A Pageant of Bible Women, 1933 (Box 227)
    - Dayton, Donald, Theological Roots of Pentecostalism, 1974 (Box 227)
    - Dunlap, E. Dale: The United Methodist System of Itinerant Ministry, 1983 and undated (Box 227)
    - Dunlap, Pamela Couture, On the Danger of Reading the Works of John Wesley, 1987 (Box 227)
    - English, John C. John Wesley and the Two Principias: A Study of Science and Religion in Eighteenth-Century England, 1988 (Box 227)
    - Feather, John, British Publishing in the Eighteenth Century: a preliminary subject analysis, 1986 (Box 227)
    - Fix, Andy, The Vicarship of Christ: John Wesley's Moravian Tradition and the Reform of Society, 1977 (Box 227)
    - Fouvy, C. Louis, Further Thoughts on Wesley's 'And can it be', 1992 (Box 227)
    - Gray, Wallace, The Place of Reason in the Theology of John Wesley, 1953 (Box 227)
    - Green, Charles A., Hymns of John Wesley, 1990 (Box 227)
    - Grislis, Egil, The Theology of Protestant Reformation: Selected Bibliography, 1968 (Box 227)
    - Hale, Joe, Statement to the British Committee of the World Methodist Council, 1978 (Box 227)